[theme music playing]
BASED ON THE KINGDOM OF THE GODS
[suspenseful music playing]
[clang]
[growling]
[water trickling]
[sighs]
You must eat, Your Royal Highness.
It is not Your Royal Highness's fault.
You did your best to save those people.
If I had stepped in sooner,
I could have saved them.
Then you would have ended up dead.
You said you must stay alive.
Did you not conspire treason
in order to stay alive?
[sighs]
I wanted to be different.
I wanted to be different from those...
who abandoned the weak.
[Seo-bi] And you were.
That is how I saw it.
I will look for some herbs
to treat the wound.
[Chang] Is he back?
[Mu-yeong] Not yet, I am afraid.
His name is still unknown.
His name Yeong-sin
as well as his identity tag are fake.
At the moment, we need someone
who knows the area well.
Did Your Royal Highness
not see him wield the rifle?
Not even palace guards are that skilled.
Those who can match that level of prowess
are the members of Chakho.
Are you talking about the elite troop
that hunts tigers?
Yes.
Since tiger hunting is dangerous,
the members are chosen
based on their fighting skills
regardless of their social status.
Many of them are quite dangerous.
They would do anything
to stay alive.
They would do anything to stay alive?
They are like me, then.
Your Royal Highness.
- [cracking]
- [gasps]
Speak to me.
No soldiers are on our tail.
I also checked a few villages on the way.
The disease has not spread yet,
but the people are terrified
by its rumors.
Judging by the vacant residences,
many villagers must have already fled.
[indistinct whispering]
[ominous music playing]
[low rumble]
[Seo-bi screams]
[swords rasp]
A monster! It is a monster!
[panting]
[whimpering]
Water. Give me some water. Water!
Is that...
Magistrate Cho?
Your Royal Highness?
Your Royal Highness. Are you really--
[grunts] Your Royal Highness, I--
[groaning]
Do you know how much blood
the people you abandoned shed?
[Mu-yeong] Please stop.
He is not even worth killing.
[groaning]
Did you not run for your life?
What happened to you?
Well, the cargo ship...
The disease spread on the ship.
What do you mean?
An infected corpse was on the ship.
The corpse infected everyone on board.
Only I was able to make it out alive.
Where is the ship now?
The disease started to spread
when we reached Seongju, so...
If that is the case,
they will reach Sangju soon.
Messengers were already sent,
so Sangju must be prepared for it.
Actually, only city-fortresses
near Dongnae were notified of the disease.
If Mungyeong Saejae in Sangju falls,
the disease will reach Hanyang in no time.
We will leave for Sangju right away.
[whimpering] Your Royal Highness!
Your Royal Highness!
Please... Let me come with you.
[ominous music playing]
[mast creaking]
[pigs oinking]
[chickens clucking]
[pig snorting]
[snarling]
[rumbling]
[Yeong-sin]
Sangju is right over that mountain!
[Chang] Once Sangju is breached,
the disease will spread
all over the nation.
We must stop it.
SANGJU
[rhythmic music playing]
[murmuring]
Are the rumors true?
- What?
- A cursed disease is spreading.
They say a headless ghost
appears in the night.
[gasps]
[Deok-seong]
A signal fire has been sent from Dongnae.
The messenger is yet to arrive,
so the local government
does not know about the details.
However,
a strange rumor is spreading
across Gyeongsang.
A disease is spreading in Dongnae,
and its victims do not seem to stay dead.
Get ready.
I am leaving the mountains.
This talisman will chase away
all diseases and ghosts.
[people exclaim]
The talisman written in cinnabar
by this young shaman is only ten bun.
Only ten bun, people!
- [man] Give me one, please.
- Here, it is ten bun.
Give me one too.
This is all I have though.
How dare you try to bargain with me!
You are bad luck. Shoo! Ten bun!
- Bring the money.
- Damn it!
[gasps] Lord Ahn Hyeon.
- Lord Ahn Hyeon!
- Lord Ahn Hyeon is here!
- [horse neighs]
- Whoa.
My lord, upon my inspection,
I found something peculiar by the stream.
You must see it for yourself.
[Ahn Hyeon]
Why is a ship that belongs to the nation
stranded here at this stream?
I suspect a huge commotion, my lord.
It must be why a signal fire
was sent from Dongnae.
[Ahn Hyeon] Giddyap!
[Chang panting]
[groans]
There is a village deep in this forest.
- Yes, of slash-and-burn farmers.
- [Beom-pal] Huh? [sniffs]
I smell... grilled meat.
[sniffs] I smell pork.
Here and on the deck,
there is blood everywhere.
The floors and walls are covered in blood,
so where are the injured or the dead?
[indistinct chattering]
[man] You never know when we will
eat again, so eat up while you can.
[villagers clamoring]
- [man 2] Eat up!
- [man 3] Do not forget to chew.
- [man 3] Do not eat too much rice.
- [man 4] This is good.
[man 3] Eat the pork...
This is odd.
People are dying of famine,
but here they eat rice and pork.
What brings you by deep into this forest?
Where is this food from?
Well,
we received it as payment
for helping out at a party.
[scoffs]
- Oh!
- [giggles]
No way.
Move. Get out of my way!
[grunts]
Step aside. I told you to move!
[woman yelps]
I see cargo from the ship!
They must have looted the ship.
I apologize!
[stuttering] Please spare my life.
We are terribly sorry.
[murmuring]
It was not our intent
to steal from the ship.
The food was just too good to pass up on.
[villagers] Please spare our lives!
Please forgive us.
Was there anyone on the ship?
Everyone was dead when we arrived.
I went to check on the ship this morning.
The passengers were gnawed at
as if animals had attacked them.
Please believe me.
What about the bodies?
Did you just leave them there?
Animals would have gotten to them,
so we buried them all.
Where did you bury them?
[shouts] Where?
You all committed a heinous crime.
However, I understand you did so
out of hunger.
If you are honest with me,
I will lessen your punishments.
Let us lead the way.
[Deok-seong] I found wheel marks!
Are we not there yet?
[man] We are almost there.
Is this the place?
What are you doing? Keep leading the way!
We know that those who steal
government property get beheaded.
What are you talking about?
We have lived long enough lives,
but our children do not deserve to die.
Without you to talk of our crimes,
our sins will stay hidden.
You damn bastards.
Do you know who you are addressing?
Lower your weapons!
This matter is graver than stealing.
If this does not get sorted,
not only you and your children
but everyone in Gyeongsang might die.
Now lead us to the corpses!
Has hunger impaired your hearing?
Where are the bodies?
You are stepping on them.
[creatures snarling]
[men screaming]
What is that?
- [growling]
- [men screaming]
[grunting]
[men screaming]
[snarls]
[groans]
[clamoring]
My lord!
[men whimpering]
[creatures snarling]
[blowing]
If you wish to live,
raise your weapons and behead them all.
[men whimpering]
[snarling]
[men screaming]
[gunshot]
[men whimpering]
[growling]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[snarling]
[Beom-pal]
Here is another wave of monsters!
[growling]
[gunshot]
- [growls]
- [grunts]
[grunts]
[screaming]
[snarling]
No. Oh, no!
Help me!
No! No!
[grunting]
[snarling]
[screaming]
- [snarling]
- [grunting]
[yelling]
[growling]
[grunting]
[panting]
[wind gusting]
[muffled sounds]
[tense music playing]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[sighs] Please come down!
Must I force you down here?
[child sobbing] I will be killed if I do.
Everyone wants me out of the palace.
If I am deposed, I will be killed.
[sobbing]
I miss my late mother.
You are not supposed to be here.
[sobbing]
[sighs]
This is not...
where you should be.
GANGNYEONGJEON
[child] I do not want to go there.
Master, I would rather go back.
[Ahn Hyeon] What you said is right.
His Majesty has received
a stack of appeals
that claim your deposition.
To make it worse,
there is no one in the palace
who can protect you.
So...
you must protect yourself.
Your Royal Highness...
is not just trying
to protect your own life.
You are in a battle against injustice.
There are those who are trying to make
the Crown Prince their puppets
for their own interest.
Fighting and winning against that evil
is the only way to uphold justice.
Show your respects!
He is the Crown Prince,
the heir to the throne!
[servants] We greet His Royal Highness!
It has been a while,
Master.
There is no lie to any of it.
Father...
has passed away.
Lord Cho, who is obsessed with power,
had Physician Lee Seung-hui
feed my father the resurrection plant
which turned him into...
a flesh-craving monster.
That is what started
the horrific epidemic.
Cho Hak-ju is as atrocious as ever.
You must help.
I will return to Hanyang,
punish the Haewon Cho Clan,
and build this nation anew.
[exhales]
When was the last time...
you had some sleep?
What do you mean?
Have you come all this way
despite the hunger
and disheveled appearance?
Thugs on the street can do so.
However...
Your Royal Highness may not.
The Crown Prince
must always...
look decent and confident.
Sangju is my hometown
and where I currently reside.
I urge you, Your Royal Highness,
to rest peacefully for tonight.
- [Deok-seong] Hurry.
- [servant] Yes, sir.
[rattling]
What kind of a man is Lord Ahn Hyeon?
Why are you asking me that?
Do you not find it odd?
Neither Lord Ahn nor his servants
were alarmed at the sight of the ill.
They swiftly beheaded
and burned the infected.
They did not hesitate
in fighting the infected.
It is as if they knew well
about the infected.
Escort His Royal Highness.
Also, find his companions a place to rest.
[servant 2] This way, Your Royal Highness.
What did Lord Ahn say?
He did not give me a definite answer.
Can he truly be trusted?
Your Royal Highness.
He may still be mourning,
but even when Lord Cho
suppressed the scholars,
Lord Ahn did not even lift a finger
to help them.
He could be in alliance with Lord Cho.
Watch what you say.
He is not one for you to speak lightly of.
- But Your Royal Highness--
- Get some rest too.
You have not been able to
these past few days.
[sighs]
PATIENT JOURNAL
HANYANG
Look here.
Why does he get food and not me?
Why? Seriously?
[sighs]
[chokes]
[retches]
[snorting]
[man] What is wrong?
[groaning]
My gosh.
Over here!
Look...
[prisoner growling]
[prisoner 2 gasps]
[snarling]
[growling]
[prisoner 2 screaming]
[screaming continues]
- [munching]
- [screaming]
[snarling]
[growling]
Feeding the flesh of the infected
to a healthy subject
leads to the transmission of the disease.
This cannot be controlled.
Before it reaches the northern region,
the epidemic must be contained.
[snoring]
[birds chirping]
[grunts]
MONUMENT TO THE BATTLE OF UNPO WETLAND
TO COMMEMORATE THE GREAT VICTORY
OF GOVERNOR AHN HYEON OF GYEONGSANG,
WHO DEFEATED 30,000 JAPANESE SOLDIERS
WITH 500 SOLDIERS
SUMANG VILLAGE
[boy sobbing] Do not go.
Please do not leave me.
Can you please stay?
Go back inside. I promise I will be back.
Please! Do not go!
[boy sobbing]
You must come back.
You must!
NORTH GATE OF SANGJU
Here comes a messenger!
Oh.
How did it go? Did you find it?
- Is this it, my lord?
- Yes, it is.
Good job.
Is that the cargo from the ship?
Yes, my lord.
Nothing disastrous happened
thanks to Lord Ahn
locating the infected heading north,
but he mentioned
to heighten security down south.
Anyway,
- is it true?
- May I ask what you are referring to?
I heard that His Royal Highness
is here in Sangju.
Is it true?
[officer] My lord!
The Five Armies have left Hanyang
and are headed for Mungyeong Saejae.
[tense music playing]
Oh! Hey, Seo-bi!
Seo-bi! [pants]
[panting]
Where have you been all by yourself?
I looked for you everywhere.
I was searching for medicinal herbs
for His Royal Highness.
Forget about the herbs.
Run away with me.
You will die if you return to his side.
- Follow me.
- What are you talking about?
The Five Armies are coming
to arrest His Royal Highness.
What?
Is that true?
Being with a man who committed treason
will ensure your death.
I am of the Haewon Cho Clan,
so I will be able to protect you. Come on!
Are you running away again?
No, well--
His Royal Highness jumped through hoops
to save the people you abandoned,
but here you are
turning your back on him again.
Is it really hard for you to show bravery
for once in your life?
Well, you see--
Run away on your own.
- I will stay with His Royal Highness.
- But, wait...
Seo-bi!
[woman 1] Slow down or you will choke.
You do not have to be greedy.
There is more, so eat up.
My goodness, you look too young
to be pregnant.
[laughing]
Here, let me take it.
Thank you for taking care
of lowly peasants like us.
There is no need to thank me.
Stop talking nonsense and just eat up.
- [women] Sure!
- Thank you.
[woman 1] Eat up and give birth to sons!
[women] Thank you.
By the way, who could it be?
Who is taking such good care of us?
How should we know? Just eat up.
[laughing]
- No one is telling us.
- Well,
I am grateful for the food
and the shelter,
but I still find it odd.
Why have they only gathered
pregnant women who have nowhere to go?
Eat up while it is all for free.
It looks like you will give birth
any time now.
[laughing]
Eat up and just pop out a healthy baby.
[woman 3] Thank you.
My lady. Yes, you.
[laughing]
How did you end up here?
You do not seem like one of us.
My husband told me to be here.
[murmuring]
What do you mean by that?
Does your husband know the master
of this household?
My husband is the Crown Prince's guard,
and he went on a trip
with His Royal Highness.
He was worried to leave me alone,
so he told me to come here.
No wonder.
I knew you were not
a pathetic widow like us.
- [women laughing]
- How sweet.
[woman 4] You have a wonderful husband.
Anyway, please eat up.
- Please enjoy.
- [woman 4] Sure.
[court lady]
Your Majesty, it is time for the assembly.
I shall go.
[eunuch] The Queen shall now enter!
[servants] We greet Her Majesty.
[drumbeat thumping]
The Court will hear
Her Majesty's royal edict.
[Hak-ju]
"Heaven gave no blessing to this nation
which led to His Majesty
suddenly falling ill
and losing consciousness.
Meanwhile, his son, the Crown Prince,
committed high treason
by desiring the throne for himself.
Such commotion
has disrupted the royal family,
and the throne is left empty.
Now, a horrendous disease
is spreading through the nation,
bringing nothing but suffering
to the people.
How is this not a tragedy?
I no longer can reject the sincere
and loyal advice
of current and retired officials
regarding the throne staying vacant,
which is why I will brace myself
and take over as Queen Regent."
[servants]
Thank you for your boundless generosity!
On her first day as Queen Regent,
Her Majesty will relay her first orders.
"To eradicate the disease
terrorizing the land of Gyeongsang,
the Five Armies consisting of
the Military Training Command,
the Royal Commandery Division,
and the Southern Fort Command
will be sent to help."
[trumpets blast]
[man] The drum indicates
that they passed the second gate.
They will be here soon.
[gasps]
I see them coming!
THE FIRST GATE OF YEONGNAM
[murmuring]
[gasping]
What is that?
[Hak-ju] "From this moment on,
the western and eastern part of Gyeongsang
will be sealed off."
Seal off the first gate!
What is going on?
What are you doing?
Why are you sealing off-- [grunts]
[head clerk] Stop!
[groaning]
[gasps]
SANGJU
[Hak-ju] "Mungyeong Saejae, the main road
that leads out of Gyeongsang
as well as all the gates of Jungnyeong,
Chupungnyeong, and Gyeripnyeong
will be sealed off.
Anyone who acts against this order
will be executed on the spot,
thus demonstrating
the seriousness of the law."
[servants]
Thank you for your boundless generosity!
[theme music playing]